The Bailey Collection
The Bailey Collection
- Notes on persons and places arranged alphabetically, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9-C.7.18; GB/418/Bailey/1; 12 sub-series; Chetham's Library
  - Names and places beginning with I, J, K and L, [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.14; GB/418/Bailey/1/9; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the career of Richard Lovelace, poet, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 38; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/41; Chetham's Library
    - Transcriptions of medieval deeds and notes on the history of Lyme co Ches., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 39; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/42; Chetham's Library
    - Transcription of 1673 Lay Subsidy of Lymm co Ches., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 40; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/43; Chetham's Library
    - Envelope containing miscellaneous notes relating to subjects beginning with 'L', 19th century; GB/418/C.7.14 no 41; GB/418/Bailey/1/9/44; Chetham's Library
      Lake, John
      Lakes, the
      Lancashire family
      Lancaster runic cross
      Langton family
      Lathome, Paul
      Lawton Church
      Layburn, James
      Lewes, Joyce
      Lightollers, the
      Livesey, Jane
      Local libraries
      Longdendale
      Long Parliament
      Lansho, Mistress
      Lorrence of Portyngale
      Love, C
      Lowe, Roger
      Lowndes, Thos. and Ralph
      Lyndewood
  - Names and places beginning with M, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15; GB/418/Bailey/1/10; Chetham's Library
    - Transcriptions of medieval charters and newspaper cuttings relating to Maghull, co Lancs., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/1; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the career of Thomas Mallory, clergyman of Mobberley, co Ches in the 17th century., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/2; Chetham's Library
    - Miscellaneous genealogical notes of the Manguall family of Lancashire., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/3; Chetham's Library
    - Pedigree and miscellaneous notes concerning the Mainwaring family of Cheshire., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/4; Chetham's Library
    - Pedigree and miscellaneous notes concerning the Marbury family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/5; Chetham's Library
    - Transcripts of letters in the Baker MSS from Robert Marsden, Archdeacon of Nottingham, to John Worthington, (1731)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/6; Chetham's Library
    - Pedigree and miscellaneous notes concerning the Martinscroft family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/7; Chetham's Library
    - Sketch pedigree of the Massy family of Cheshire, showing descent from R[ichar]d Mascie (d 1689)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/8; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the career, writings and family of Nathaniel Mather, clergyman (b 1630, d 1697)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/9; Chetham's Library
    - Pedigree of Molyneux of Sefton., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/10; Chetham's Library
      Transcripts of medieval deeds and miscellaneous notes.
    - Notes and letter concerning of John Moon, clergyman in the 17th century., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/11; Chetham's Library
    - Extracts from charters made by John, Earl of Mortain (later King John, 1199-1216)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 12; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/12; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the writings and career of Thomas Morton, Bishop of Durham, (b 1564 d 1659)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 13; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/13; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters, transcriptions of manuscripts and sketch pedigrees concerning the Mosley family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 14; GB/418/Bailey/1/10/14; Chetham's Library
    - Envelope containing miscellaneous notes relating to subjects beginning with 'M'., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 14(i); GB/418/Bailey/1/10/15; Chetham's Library
      Machin, John
      Man, Isle of. Clergy.
      Manchester, Earl of
      Malpas, Rectors of
      Maps of Lancashire
      Marsh family
      Marshalls of Urswick
      Masher, Thomas
      Masterdon Mrs
      Meade, Thomas
      'Meols' (Great and Little) Origin of the word
      Mersey, River
      Metcalf, Captain
      Middleton School
      Midgley family of Rochdale
      Milton
      Menvale, Abbot
      Moore, Jonas
      Morton, Countess
      Moss family
      Mottram, vicar of
      Muchland or Gleaston Castle
  - Names and places beginning with N, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15; GB/418/Bailey/1/11; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the writings and career of Henry Newcome, 17th century nonconformist clergyman., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 15; GB/418/Bailey/1/11/1; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the writings and career of Thomas Newton, writer and schoolmaster, (d 1607)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 16; GB/418/Bailey/1/11/2; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the career of William Nicholson, Bishop of Lambeth, (d 1727)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 17; GB/418/Bailey/1/11/3; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of a document from the Court of Requests Bills & Answers concerning the property of William Nicholson, of the Woodhall in Reddish co Lancs., (1597); GB/418/C.7.15 no 18; GB/418/Bailey/1/11/4; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of the obituary of Rev J Nightingale, 19th century Lancashire minister, fromThe Gentleman's Magazine., 1824; GB/418/C.7.15 no 19; GB/418/Bailey/1/11/5; Chetham's Library
    - Copy of the epitaph of Jeremiah Norris at St. Michael's Church in Norwich, (b 1630 d 1700)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 20; GB/418/Bailey/1/11/6; Chetham's Library
    - 19th century transcript of charter concerning the family of Noton of Chadderton., (1234); GB/418/C.7.15 no 21; GB/418/Bailey/1/11/7; Chetham's Library
      With a letter from John Noton to J. E. Bailey concerning Noton family history, 22 Sep 1885.
  - Names and places beginning with O, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15; GB/418/Bailey/1/12; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the history of the Ogden family of Manchester., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 22; GB/418/Bailey/1/12/1; Chetham's Library
    - Notes relating to Oldham., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 23; GB/418/Bailey/1/12/2; Chetham's Library
      Map of Oldham c 1800.
    - 19th century transcript of a final concord concerning lands in Otterborne., (1596); GB/418/C.7.15 no 24; GB/418/Bailey/1/12/3; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning the writings of Charles Owen, (18th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 25; GB/418/Bailey/1/12/4; Chetham's Library
    - Envelope containing miscellaneous notes relating to subjects beginning with 'N' and 'O'., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.15 no 25(i); GB/418/Bailey/1/12/5; Chetham's Library
      Napier, GW
      Newton Heath
      Northwell, W de
      Norris of Speke
      Nowell, Dean
      Nowell, Increase
      Nutter family
      Oldfield family
      Oliver, P
  - Names and places beginning with P, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16; GB/418/Bailey/1/13; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the life and works of John Paget, minister of Amsterdam, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/1; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the origins, history and definition of the German Palatines., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/2; Chetham's Library
    - 'Notes on the duration of English Parliaments in the 17th century' by W. D. Pink, published in theLeigh Chronicle., 1886; GB/418/C.7.16 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/3; Chetham's Library
      Leigh Chronicle
    - Newspaper cuttings of two articles on Charles Stewart Parnell and the Parnells of Congleton., 1881; GB/418/C.7.16 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/4; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters on the career, writings and family of Richard Parr, Bishop of Sodor and Man, 17th century., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/5; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of a note by James Crossley on 'The History and Adventures of Godfrey Ranger; in three Volumes' by D. W. Paynter., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/6; Chetham's Library
      Described as "the first three-volume novel printed and published in Manchester by a Manchester author". Transcribed from Crossley's "copy of Godfrey Ranger in poss[essio]n of Mr Sutton, Jan 1886".
    - Letter from J. Foster to J. E. Bailey concerning register entries, 18 Oct 1877., GB/418/C.7.16 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/7; Chetham's Library
      Letter from J. [Owen] to J. E. Bailey, enclosing a short list of entries from a burial register relating to members of the Abraham and Pennington families from 1582-1683, [c 1877].
    - Transcription of the obituary of Samuel Peploe fromThe Gentleman's Magazine., (1846); GB/418/C.7.16 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/8; Chetham's Library
      The Gentleman's Magazine
    - Letter from Joseph Smith Junior to J. E. Bailey, enclosing a copy of a broadside relating to the fair held at Prescot, co Lancs., 14 Sep 1883; GB/418/C.7.16 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/9; Chetham's Library
    - Drawings of ancient crosses and font at Prestbury, co Ches., 28 May 1881; GB/418/C.7.16 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/10; Chetham's Library
    - Miscellaneous notes on the history of Preston, co Lancs., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/11; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters and sketch pedigree concerning the Prestwich family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 12; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/12; Chetham's Library
    - Collection of transcripts of medieval deeds and notes relating to Prestwich, co Lancs., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 13; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/13; Chetham's Library
    - Transcripts and cutting relating to William Prynne, Henry Burton and Dr John Bastwick., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 14; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/14; Chetham's Library
      With transcript of a manuscript relating to Prynne, made by H[enry] Fishwick, (1641).
    - Envelope containing miscellaneous notes relating to subjects beginning with 'P'., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 14(i); GB/418/Bailey/1/13/15; Chetham's Library
      Parkall, Dr
      Parker, JL
      Parkes, Mr of Bolton
      Parkinson family
      Parry family
      Patten, Thomas
      Patteson, Matthew
    - Brief note concerning John Pepys, with reference to a document in the Rawlinson MSS dated 1673., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 15; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/16; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the Piccope MSS, John Piccope, antiquary, and the Piccope family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 16; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/17; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the career of James Pilkington, vicar of Kendal, (16th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 17; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/18; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters on the history of the Plungern (also Plungeon, Plungen) family of Manchester, mostly in 17th century., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 18; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/19; Chetham's Library
      Deed (?draft or copy) involving William Plungen, dated 1697. (Paper).
    - Notes on the history of the Podmore family of Cheshire., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 19; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/20; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from Spencer Geo[rge] Percival to J. E. Bailey, enclosing printed notes on the history Poulett family of Somerset., 21 Jun 1886; GB/418/C.7.16 no 20; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/21; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning the Hooker family and poor scholars at Oxford., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 21; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/22; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the activities of the Presbyterian Classis in Lancashire., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 22; GB/418/Bailey/1/13/23; Chetham's Library
  - Names and places beginning with R, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16; GB/418/Bailey/1/14; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the history of the Radcliffe family of Ordsall, co Lancs, with brief sketch pedigree and coat of arms., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 23; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/1; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the will and inventory of Stephen Radley of Manchester, (d ?1630)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 24; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/2; Chetham's Library
    - Notes onThe Experienced English Housekeeper by Elizabeth Raffald of Manchester, first published in 1769., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 25; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/3; Chetham's Library
      The Experienced English Housekeeper
    - Notes on the family, writings and collections of Canon F. R. Raines of Milnrow, (b 1805 d 1878)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 26; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/4; Chetham's Library
      Includes a cutting fromThe Manchester Courier and Advertiser concerning the sale of his library, 19 Dec 1878.
    - Notes and letters on the Rathband family, nonconformist ministers, 17th century., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 27; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/5; Chetham's Library
    - 19th century transcript from State Papers Domestic of Ralph Rawson's petition for rectorship of Hazeley in Oxfordshire., (Aug 1660); GB/418/C.7.16 no 28; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/6; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from J. Frank Wright to J. E. Bailey, concerning Revolution House, Whittington., 11 Jul 1884; GB/418/C.7.16 no 29; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/7; Chetham's Library
    - Remarks and discussion on Rhodocanakis, pretender to the Kingdom of Rhodes in the 10th century., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 30; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/8; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning the Richardson family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 31; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/9; Chetham's Library
      With sketch pedigree showing descent from Rev Chr[istopher] Richardson (d 1698).
    - Large collection of notes, letters, cuttings and pedigrees concerning the Rigby family of Wigan and Kenyon family of Peele Hall, co Lancs., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 32; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/10; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from W. D. Macray to J. E. Bailey asking for information concerning Edmund Rishton., 2 & 5 Jan 1886; GB/418/C.7.16 no 33; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/11; Chetham's Library
      Letter from Joseph Fellow to J. E. Bailey concerning Edward Rishton (fl 16th century).
    - Notes on the life and works of Nehemiah Rogers, Minister of Lessing in Essex, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 34; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/12; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters and newspaper cuttings on Roman Roads, especially the road over Blackstone Edge., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 35; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/13; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the life and work Roscoe, historian and poet (d 1831)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 36; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/14; Chetham's Library
      With examples of his poetry.
    - Letter from M. Brierley to J. E. Bailey concerning the site of Colonel Rosworm's fortification., 10 Apr 1884; GB/418/C.7.16 no 37; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/15; Chetham's Library
      Also a note signed by Thomas Baker concerning a miniature of Rosworm, 29 Jun 1858.
    - Letter from [?W. Niper] to J. E. Bailey with notes on the career of John Rotherham MD, (b 1719, d 1787)., 14 Jan 1886; GB/418/C.7.16 no 38; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/16; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on "Gower's Life of Richard Rothwell"., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 39; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/17; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of the will of John Rowlinson of Manchester, (d 1657)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 40; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/18; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the history of Rufford and Martin Mere, co Lancs., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 41; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/19; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from [?] to J. E. Bailey, with notes and pedigrees concerning Rylands of Budworth., 11 Feb 1881; GB/418/C.7.16 no 42; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/20; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning the family history of Peter Rylands, agent for sequestration of Royalist estates., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 43; GB/418/Bailey/1/14/21; Chetham's Library
      With a transcription of his will, (27 Oct 1662).
    - Envelope containing miscellaneous notes relating to subjects beginning with 'R'., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.16 no 43(i); GB/418/Bailey/1/14/22; Chetham's Library
      Rand, Samuel
      Rawstorne, Lawrence
      Redish family
      Richmond, Sylvester
      Roads, Derby to Chatsworth
      Robin Hood
      Rochdale
      Roe, Rev. Richard
      Roman Bridge at Marple
      Root, Henry
      Rushworth, John
      Rutter, Samuel
      Rylance of Ellerton
  - Names and places beginning with S, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17; GB/418/Bailey/1/15; Chetham's Library
    - 19th century transcript of a letter from the Archbishop of York to Lord Salisbury, Early 17th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 1 (i); GB/418/Bailey/1/15/1; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from Henry Fishwick to J. E. Bailey, with a list of dates relating to [?Scholes family members]., 19 Feb 1884; GB/418/C.7.17 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/2; Chetham's Library
      With notes and monumental inscriptions concerning the Scholes family, (17th century).
    - Notes and letters concerning Rev John Shaw and the Shaw family of Saddleworth co Yorks., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/3; Chetham's Library
    - Brief note on Richard Shuttleworth of Gawthrop, co Lancs (1704/5)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/4; Chetham's Library
      With shorthand notes headed "Shuttleworth Col Oughtred".
    - 19th century copy of will of Gerard Simkin of Manchester., (c 1650); GB/418/C.7.17 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/5; Chetham's Library
    - Miscellaneous notes (mostly shorthand) concerning the Skinner family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/6; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning Thomas Sorocold and the Sorocold family of Lancashire., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/7; Chetham's Library
    - Printed pedigree of the Sotheron (also Sotheran) family of Mitton, Newcastle-on-Tyne, Holm-in-Spaldingmore, Darrington, Ampleforth, Oswaldkirk etc, compiled by Charles Sotheran of Torquay., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/8; Chetham's Library
      Beginning with the descent from Ralph de Mitton of Mitton, co Yorks (c 1066).
    - Notes, letters, cuttings and copies of documents concerning the Standish family, Standish co Lancs and its parish church., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/9; Chetham's Library
      Includes schedule of Standish deeds from 1286.
    - Notes concerning members of the Staninough family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 8 (i); GB/418/Bailey/1/15/10; Chetham's Library
      With variant spellings of the surname.
    - Notes, letters, sketch pedigree and newspaper cuttings concerning the Stanley family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/11; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters and cuttings concerning the history of Stockport, especially that of the parish church., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/12; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the career of Joshua Stopford, 17th century clergyman., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/13; Chetham's Library
    - Small bundle of extracts from Stretford chapel registers, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 11 (i); GB/418/Bailey/1/15/14; Chetham's Library
      Contains some shorthand.
    - Notes on the career and paintings of George Stubbs, artist, (b 1724)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 12; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/15; Chetham's Library
    - Slips listing the publications of the Surtees Society., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 13; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/16; Chetham's Library
    - Copy of a letter of attorney to receive seisin of land in Swineshead, co Lincs, and the advowson of a church (dated 1492)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 14; GB/418/Bailey/1/15/17; Chetham's Library
    - Envelope containing miscellaneous notes relating to subjects beginning with 'S'., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 14 (i); GB/418/Bailey/1/15/18; Chetham's Library
      Sacheverell family
      Saddleworth
      Saltmarsh
      Saxton, C
      Scarisbrick, Jesuits school at
      Schofield family
      Seddons
      Shakespeare, Edward
      Shalcross, R. and T.
      Sharp, John, a carmelite
      Shaw, Peter
      Sherburn family
      Sherlock, Richard
      Shippen, Dr
      Shuttleworth family
      Simmons, Rector of Middleton
      Singleton family
      'Sir' as applied to priests
      Smith, John
      Smith Dr, Dean of Chester
      Smith, Thomas
      Stanley family
      Stanhope, John
      Stansfield, James
      Stanley, Lawrence
      Sterry, Peter
      Stockmerton, James
      Syddall, Thomas
  - Names and places beginning with T, U and V, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17; GB/418/Bailey/1/16; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and a newspaper cutting concerning the will of Nicholas Talbot of Bury St Edmunds made in 1501., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 15; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/1; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of the obituary of Mrs Jane Tarleton of Liverpool (d 1797) taken fromThe Gentleman's Magazine., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 16; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/2; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning Charles Tavare, 19th century poet, written by Frederick Lawrence Tavare and addressed to the editor ofThe Palatine Note-Book., GB/418/C.7.17 no 17; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/3; Chetham's Library
      The Palatine Note-Book
    - Original manuscript letter from John Taylor of Kirkbie Hill to the Worshipfull Mr Christopher Anderton esq at his dwelling house at Birchley or Lostock, concerning repairs to his house., 1 Aug 1617; GB/418/C.7.17 no 17 (i); GB/418/Bailey/1/16/4; Chetham's Library
      With 19th century transcription.
    - Notes on the career of John Tillinghast (also Tillinghurst), 17th century clergyman., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 18; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/5; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters, cuttings and transcriptions of documents concerning the life and works of John Tilsley, 17th century minister at Deane., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 19; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/6; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning Todmorden co Yorks, much in shorthand., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 19 (i); GB/418/Bailey/1/16/7; Chetham's Library
      Includes "Robert Dawson's Constables Accounts for the Year 1736".
    - Collection of notes and letters concerning the history and estates of the Towneley family of Towneley, near Burnley, co Lancs., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 20; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/8; Chetham's Library
    - Two letters from W. Reynell to J. E. Bailey concerning Richard Chevenix Trench, Archbishop in Ireland, (d 1884), with brief notes., 30 Mar & 2 Apr [188?]; GB/418/C.7.17 no 21; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/9; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the history of the Tunstall family of Yorkshire., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 22; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/10; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and press cuttings on Turton Tower and its owners (including Humphrey Chetham)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 23; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/11; Chetham's Library
      Includes inventory of contents of the Tower.
    - Envelope containing miscellaneous notes relating to subjects beginning with 'T'., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17 no 24; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/12; Chetham's Library
      Talbot, John
      Taylors of Heywood
      Taylor, John (water poet)
      Taylor, Zachary
      'Thirkyll' Mr
      'Throughs'
      Tildesly family
      Tillotson, Archbishop
      Timperley's Lancashire Collections
      Tipping family
      Torshell, S.
      Townsheads
      Trafford family
      Travers, Rev P of Halsall
      Travis family of Blackley
    - Notes concerning the Upton family, including James Upton of King's College, Cambridge, an eminent scholar and critic (b 1670)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.17, bundle 10 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/13; Chetham's Library
    - 19th century transcript of a petition sent to Richard Vaughan, Bishop of Chester, concerning the illegal marriage of Hugh Harrison of Aldford, co Ches., (1599); GB/418/C.7.17, bundle 10 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/1/16/14; Chetham's Library